I never really got excited about the
concept of retirement.
Hey,
you're going to work really hard at
school, stay out of trouble.
You're going to go to university,
get in loads of debt.
You're going to get a nine till five.
You're going to work really hard.
You're going to pay off all your debt,
and then just when you pay off that debt,
you're going to get another debt, and
that debt is going to be massive, and it's
going to be for a house,
and you're going to pay it off for 30
years.
So if you buy a house at 25,
which no one is, most of them
are buying them at what,
30 to 35. Thirty years,
that takes you to 65.
So then you're just paying off debt.
And then at 65, you've paid off
that debt and now you can stop
working. And then you get your pension,
which is a lot less of the money that you
used to earn,
but now you haven't got debt
and you might own your house or you
might not. And then you're 65 now,
you can travel the
world and do all of those things
that you couldn't do because you only had
two
weeks of annual leave a year for the last
60 years. That never excited me.
I was like, hmm. Between 25 and 35,
I have less than half the energy
that I had at
25. So at 45, if that halves again,
trust me, by the time I reach 65,
I'm just going to want to sit at home on a
rocking chair, being left alone.
The idea of having to wait decades to be
able to enjoy yourself never
resonated me. So when I read this book
and I was like, wow, retirement
is actually
a worst-case scenario.
If you never make anything of your life
and your
businesses never do that well,
then maybe you give up at 65 and retire.
But for some reason,
we're kind of brainwashed into thinking
that's the best
outcome. Now, hypocritically,
my dad retired. He loves it.
Absolutely loves it.
Does nothing with his days.
He's feeding ducks with a bit of bread in
the garden.
He even somehow realized there
were Egyptian geese at the top of a tree.
He can barely use WhatsApp,
so I don't know how he figured that out.
But for me, I'm not saying for everyone,
but for me, I couldn't imagine anything
worse than retiring